# PHILIP BROWNE

 • Washington DC/Baltimore | ☐ (443) 459-7382 | ☑ pbrowne@gmail.com | ♠ PhilipBrowne | Im PhilipBrowneTech | ∰ www.philiprowne.com

Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for helping people through technology and finding ways to efficiently and collaboratively solve problems. Dedicated and detail-oriented professional with a background of more than a decade as an orchestral musician and a proven record of success in multiple industries.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Go/Golang

Libraries and Frameworks: Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Flask, REST, GraphQL, gRPC, Selenium

Databases: SQL (PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL), MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Neo4j, DynamoDB

Testing: Jasmine, Jest, React Test Library, PyTest

CI/CD & Deployment: Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Jenkins, GitHub, GitLab

# **PROJECTS**

### Voter Info / Repository Link

2021

Full-Stack Voter Information Application using Google Civic Information, EasyPost, and MapQuest APIs

• Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Axios, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL

# Space Force / Repository Link

2021

- Full-Stack Platform Game developed for Mintbean.io Hiring Hackathon built with PhaserJS Library. Mintbean Star Award Winner for "exemplary achievement in the field of web development"
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, PhaserJS, JavaScript State Machine, Bootstrap, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy PostgreSQL

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Junior Full Stack Developer

2021 - Present

M-Partners Incorporated

- Develop and maintain both independent and collaborative projects for small startup specializing in new concepts in data analytics, artificial intelligence, and machine learning to enable automatic end-to-end data collection, processing, and analysis.
- Build scalable highly reliable products and maintaining uptime of existing applications.

#### **Communications Administrator / Technical Support**

2021

Unitarian Universalist Church of Silver Spring

- Served as Office Administrator for 200+ member congregation as the central point of contact and technical support.
- Managed membership database and found ways to effectively promote congregation, while also managing UUCSS Website via WordPress platform.

Freelance Musician 2009 – Present

 Professional Orchestral French Horn player with experience working with groups such as the Baltimore Symphony, Virginia Symphony, Richmond Symphony, Pittsburgh Opera, and National Philharmonic, among others.

# **EDUCATION**

# Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland

Graduated with BM in 2009, GPD in 2012

Bachelor of Music, French Horn Performance; Graduate Performance Diploma (GPD), French Horn Performance

# Yale University Graduate School of Music

2012-2014

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track Fellowship

2021

An 800-hour fellowship that covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Modules include learning resources, practice exercises, projects, and career-related coursework.